

# **Aleksei Borodin**

# Java Software Engineer

+79514877380 | +998947043877

swizbizy@gmail.com

▼ telegram.me/swizbiz

in linkedin.com/in/aleksei-borodin

github.com/swizbiz

dzone.com/users/4755732/swizbiz.html

I'm passionate Software engineer with 5+ years of experience in IT and 4 years in Java. I have extensive hands-on experience in Java, Kotlin and Groovy languages, Spring framework, Hibernate, Microservices. I'm always open for new technologies and opportunities to improve my skills. I also leadan active and diverse lifestyle. And I have awesome mustache;)

### **EDUCATION**

Master's Degree in Computer Science Information security of automated systems Chelyabinsk State University - 2011 - 2016

### CERTIFICATES

2019, Base course of Java - Certificate of completion with honors, Computer Science Center

2019, Java Developer Course, JavaRush

# **LANGUAGES**

English - B2 Russian - Native

### **SKILLS**

- Base: Java 17, Groovy, Kotlin, OOP, SOLID.
- Frameworks: Spring (Boot, Data, Security, MVC, Cloud), Vert.X, RxJava, Hibernate.
- · DevOps: Kubernetes, Docker, Openshift, Git, Jenkins, SonarQube, GitHub Actions.
- Build tools: Maven, Gradle, Jib.
- Test: JUnit, Testcontainers, Mockito, TDD.
- Databases: Oracle, PostgreSQL, Liquibase.
- Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana, JMeter, Dynatrace, Java Flight Record(JFR).
- Profiling: Eclipse MAT, JProfiler, VisualVM.
- Other: BitBucket, Swagger, OpenAPI, Jira, Confluence, GraphQL, Scrum, Agile, Kanban.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Java Software Engineer

Mar 2022 - Present

**HUAWEI** 

Project: Artipie - binary artifact management tools, similar to Artifactory.

- Implemented a new repository adapter for Erlang and Elixir languages. Artipie is the first and only one with support for Elixir/Erlang packages.
- Researched the QUIC protocol to support HTTP/3 in the Huawei Cloud.
- Implemented and contributed to an open source GitHub Action to automatically update the year in the license files.
- Wrote articles about Artipie to promote it in developer community. Technologies: Java 17, Vert.X, RxJava, Reactive Streams, Docker, Maven, GitHub Actions, JUnit, Testcontainers, Prometheus, Grafana.

# Java Software Engineer

Oct 2019 - Mar 2022

**SBERBANK** 

Project: SberFriend - employee interaction service for performing official and organizational tasks within the SberBank ecosystem. Developed backend for low-code platform for creation micro-application(similar to apps in WeChat) for SberFriend.

- Split monolith running on IBM WebSphere into microservices on Spring Boot, that run in OpenShift, which reduced time to market by 7 times.
- Migrated the database from Oracle to PostgreSQL, which allowed removing the vendor lock and reduce license costs.
- Automated the process of passing the task through the life cycle reduce manual processing tasks from 700 to 30 tasks per day.
- Developed a plugin for Intellij Idea for internal micro-applications, which helps to create, test, build a package of micro-applications and deploy it directly from Idea.

Technologies: Java 7->11, Groovy, Kotlin, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Maven, Gradle, Jenkins, IBM WebSphere->Openshift, JUnit, Mockito, Docker, Oracle->PostgreSQL, Liquibase, SonarQube, Prometheus, Grafana, Dynatrace, BitBucket, Swagger, OpenAPI, Eclipse MAT, VisualVM.

# Java Developer **TOPJAVA**

May 2019 - Sep 2019

• Developed an enterprise application with authorization and role-based access rights, storage in database and deploy to a Heroku cloud platform. <u>Technologies</u>: Java 11, Spring(Core, MVC, Security, Data), JDBC, JPA, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, HSQLDB, H2, Maven, Heroku, RESTful API, JUnit, Mockito, Java Script, Bootstrap, jQuery.

# 1C Developer

Jan 2018 - Sep 2019

1C-RARUS

• Developed and optimized the company's business processes to optimize the coordination of revenue contracts - increase in profits of 17%. Technologies: 1C, PostgreSQL, SQL, Linux, Bash.